It's a wonderful laugh! It's a wonderful love!
It's a Wonderful Life is a drama, family, fantasy film directed by Frank Capra.
George Bailey has spent his entire life giving to the people of Bedford Falls.
All that prevents rich skinflint Mr.
Potter from taking over the entire town is George's
modest building and loan company.
But on Christmas Eve the business's $8,000 is lost and George's troubles begin.
George Bailey, played by James Stewart.
Mary Hatch, played by Donna Reed.
Mr. Potter, played by Lionel Barrymore.
Uncle Billy, played by Thomas Mitchell.
Clarence, played by Henry Travers.
Mrs. Bailey, played by Beulah Bondi.
It's a Wonderful Life is a 1946 American Christmas fantasy and
drama film directed and produced by Frank Capra.
It is based on the short story and booklet "The Greatest Gift", self-published by Philip Van Doren Stern in
1943, which itself is loosely based on the 1843 Charles Dickens novella A Christmas Carol.
The film stars James Stewart as George Bailey, a man who has given up his personal dreams to help others in his community and
whose intended suicide on Christmas Eve brings about the intervention of his guardian angel, Clarence Odbody.
Clarence shows George all the lives he touched and what the
world would be like if he had not existed.
Although it was nominated for five Academy Awards, including Best Picture,  It's a Wonderful
Life initially received mixed reviews and was unsuccessful at the box office.
Theatrically, the film's break-even point was $6.3 million, about twice the production
cost, a figure it did not come close to achieving on its initial release.
Because of the film's disappointing sales, Capra was seen by some studios as having
lost his ability to produce popular, financially successful films.
Its copyright in the U.S.
expired in 1974 following a lack of renewal and it entered the public domain, allowing it to be
broadcast without licensing or royalty fees, at which point it became a Christmas classic.
It's a Wonderful Life is now considered to be one of the greatest
films of all time and among the best Christmas films.
It has been recognized by the American Film Institute as one
of the 100 best American films ever made.
11 on the American Film Institute's 1998 greatest movie list, no.
20 on its 2007 greatest movie list, no.
8 on its list of greatest love stories, and no.
1 on its list of the most inspirational American films of all time.
In 1990, It's a Wonderful Life became one of 25 films selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry
by the Library of Congress for being deemed as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
Capra revealed that it was his favorite among the films he directed and
that he screened it for his family every Christmas season.
It was one of Stewart's favorite films.
A modern remake of the film, written and directed by Kenya Barris, is in
development at Paramount Pictures as of January 2024.
The film explores themes of small town, angel, suicide attempt, holiday, bank.
The tone is emotional.